[{"question":" Which command adds members to the replica set from MongoDB shell?","options":[{"text":"`rs.add(\"<hostname>\")`","correct":true},{"text":"`replicaSetAdd(\"<hostname>\")`","correct":false},{"text":"`rs.insert(\"<hostname>\")`","correct":false},{"text":"`replica.add(\"<hostname>\")`","correct":false}],"illustrator":""},{"question":" Which MongoDB shell command should you use to back up a database?","options":[{"text":"restore","correct":false},{"text":"backup","correct":false},{"text":"mongobackup","correct":false},{"text":"mongodump","correct":true}],"illustrator":""},{"question":" Which shell query displays all citizens with an age greater than or equal to 21?","options":[{"text":"`db.citizens.select('WHERE age >= 21')`","correct":false},{"text":"`db.citizens.where('age >= 21')`","correct":false},{"text":"`db.citizens.find('WHERE age >= 21')`","correct":false},{"text":"`db.citizens.find({age: {$gte: 21}})`","correct":true}],"illustrator":""},{"question":" What does a MongoDB collection consist of?","options":[{"text":"data","correct":false},{"text":"documents","correct":true},{"text":"fields","correct":false},{"text":"rows","correct":false}],"illustrator":""},{"question":" Given an ObjectId in \\_id, how do you get the time it was created?","options":[{"text":"getDateTime(\\_id)","correct":false},{"text":"\\_id.createDate()","correct":false},{"text":"\\_id.getTimestamp()","correct":true},{"text":"\\_id.getDateTime()","correct":false}],"illustrator":""},{"question":" Given a cursor named myCursor, which command returns a boolean value?","options":[{"text":"myCursor.hasNext()","correct":true},{"text":"myCursor.sort()","correct":false},{"text":"myCursor.next()","correct":false},{"text":"myCursor.find()","correct":false}],"illustrator":""},{"question":" Which command returns a specific document in the user's collection?","options":[{"text":"db.users.find({\\_id: 1})","correct":true},{"text":"db.users.seek({\\_id: 1})","correct":false},{"text":"db.users.query({\\_id: 1})","correct":false},{"text":"db.query.users({\\_id: 1})","correct":false}],"illustrator":""},{"question":" To import a JSON array into Mongo, what flags are needed with MongoDBimport?","options":[{"text":"`--type jsonArray`","correct":false},{"text":"`--json`","correct":false},{"text":"`--type json`","correct":false},{"text":"`--jsonArray`","correct":true}],"illustrator":""},{"question":" Choose the shell command that connects to a MongoDB database.","options":[{"text":"mongo","correct":true},{"text":"mongod","correct":false},{"text":"mongoconnect","correct":false},{"text":"dbconnect","correct":false}],"illustrator":""},{"question":". In the MongoDB shell, how can you tell if an index was used with a query?","options":[{"text":"db.customers.find({lastName: 'smith'}).explain()","correct":true},{"text":"db.customers.find({lastName: 'smith'}).perf()","correct":false},{"text":"db.customers.find({lastName: 'smith'}).plan()","correct":false},{"text":"db.customers.find({lastName: 'smith'}).usedIndex()","correct":false}],"illustrator":""},{"question":". Suppose your aggregation pipeline terminated with an exception referring to exceeded memory limit. What is the best way to resolve the issue?","options":[{"text":"Set useMemory to twice amount indicated in exception.","correct":false},{"text":"Switch a 64 bit instance of MongoDB.","correct":false},{"text":"Increase the memory of the MongoDB server.","correct":false},{"text":"Set allowDiskUse to true.","correct":true}],"illustrator":""},{"question":". What is the recommended way to delete a user?","options":[{"text":"db.deleteUser(\"user\")","correct":false},{"text":"db.removeUser(\"user\") DEPRECATED","correct":false},{"text":"db.remove(\"user\")","correct":false},{"text":"db.dropUser(\"user\")","correct":true}],"illustrator":""},{"question":". What the primary database in a replica set fails, when does failover begin?","options":[{"text":"once the primary has been down for 10 minutes","correct":false},{"text":"once the primary reboots","correct":false},{"text":"immediately","correct":true},{"text":"after the administrator reboots the primary","correct":false}],"illustrator":""},{"question":". What is the correct option to set up Kerberos when starting MongoDBd?","options":[{"text":"`--setParameter authenticationMechanisms=GSSAPI`","correct":true},{"text":"`--setAuthentication=GSSAPI`","correct":false},{"text":"`--setParam auth=K`","correct":false},{"text":"`--setAuth method=Kerberos`","correct":false}],"illustrator":""},{"question":". What is the purpose of an arbiter in a replica set?","options":[{"text":"It monitors replica set and sends email in case of failure","correct":false},{"text":"It casts the tie-breaking vote in an election.","correct":true},{"text":"It holds a backup copy of the database.","correct":false},{"text":"It reboots the failed server.","correct":false}],"illustrator":""},{"question":". You want to know how many types of items you have in each category. Which query does this?","options":[{"text":"`db.product.group({_id: \"$category\", count: {$sum:1}})`","correct":false},{"text":"`db.product.aggregate($sum: {_id: \"$category\", count: {$group:1}})`","correct":false},{"text":"`db.product.aggregate($group: {_id: \"$category\", count: {$sum:1}})`","correct":true},{"text":"`db.product.aggregate($count: {_id: \"$category\", count: {$group:1}})`","correct":false}],"illustrator":""},{"question":". To restrict the number of records coming back from a query, which command should you use?","options":[{"text":"take","correct":false},{"text":"limit","correct":true},{"text":"max","correct":false},{"text":"skip","correct":false}],"illustrator":""},{"question":". You have a collection named restaurants with the geographical information stored in the location property, how do you create a geospatial index on it?","options":[{"text":"`db.restaurants.CreateIndex({location: \"2dsphere\"})`","correct":true},{"text":"`db.restaurants.geospatial({location: \"2dsphere\"})`","correct":false},{"text":"`db.restaurants.CreateIndex(\"2dsphere\":\"location\")`","correct":false},{"text":"`db.restaurants.CreateIndex({geospatial: \"location\"})`","correct":false}],"illustrator":""},{"question":". How do you find documents with a matching item in an embedded array?","options":[{"text":"`db.customers.findmatch ({\"jobs\":\"secretary\"})`","correct":false},{"text":"`db.customers.find ({\"jobs:secretary\"})`","correct":false},{"text":"`db.customers.find ({\"jobs\":[\"secretary\"]})`","correct":false},{"text":"`db.customers.find ({\"jobs\":\"secretary\"})`","correct":true}],"illustrator":""},{"question":". Which query bypasses the first 5 customers and returns the next 10?","options":[{"text":"`db.customers.find({}, {skip: 5, limit: 10})`","correct":false},{"text":"`db.customers.find({}.page(5).take(10))`","correct":false},{"text":"`db.customers.find({}).skip(5).take(10)`","correct":false},{"text":"`db.customers.find({}).skip(5).limit(10)`","correct":true}],"illustrator":""},{"question":". How do you create a text index?","options":[{"text":"`db.customers.createIndex({firstName, lastName})`","correct":false},{"text":"`db.customers.createTextIndex({firstName, lastName})`","correct":false},{"text":"`db.customers.createIndex({firstName: \"text\", lastName: \"text\"})`","correct":true},{"text":"`db.customers.createText({firstName: 1, lastName: 1})`","correct":false}],"illustrator":""},{"question":". Assuming you have customers collection with a firstName and lastName field, which is the correct MongoDB shell command to create an index on lastName, then firstName both ascending?","options":[{"text":"`db.customers.createIndex(\"lastName, firstName, ASC\")`","correct":false},{"text":"`db.customers.addIndex({lastName:\"ASC\", firstName: \"ASC\"})`","correct":false},{"text":"`db.customers.newIndex({lastName:1, firstName:1})`","correct":false},{"text":"`db.customers.createIndex({lastName:1, firstName: 1})`","correct":true}],"illustrator":""},{"question":". One of the documents in your collection has an \\_id based upon an older database design and you want to change it. You write an update command to find the document and replace the \\_id but the \\_id isn't changed. How should you fix the issue?","options":[{"text":"Set the replace option to true.","correct":false},{"text":"Use the replaceOne() command instead.","correct":false},{"text":"You can't. Once set, the \\_id field cannot be changed.","correct":true},{"text":"Use the updateOne() command instead.","correct":false}],"illustrator":""},{"question":". A compound index allows you to \\_\\_\\_ ?","options":[{"text":"Calculate interest quickly.","correct":false},{"text":"Accomplish nothing, since compound indexes aren't allowed in Mongo.","correct":false},{"text":"Use more than one field per index.","correct":false},{"text":"Combine fields in different collations.","correct":true}],"illustrator":""},{"question":". Why are ad-hoc queries useful?","options":[{"text":"They do not have to use the same operators.","correct":false},{"text":"You do not need to structure the database to support them.","correct":false},{"text":"They autogenerate reports.","correct":false},{"text":"They run faster than indexed queries.","correct":true}],"illustrator":""},{"question":". How often do the members of a replica set send heartbeats to each other?","options":[{"text":"every 2 minutes","correct":false},{"text":"every 5 seconds","correct":false},{"text":"every 2 seconds","correct":true},{"text":"every 10 seconds","correct":false}],"illustrator":""},{"question":". Which command returns all of the documents in the customers collection?","options":[{"text":"`db.customers.all();`","correct":false},{"text":"`db.find().customers();`","correct":false},{"text":"`db.customers.find();`","correct":true},{"text":"`db.customers.show();`","correct":false}],"illustrator":""},{"question":". Given a cursor named myCursor, pointing to the customers collection, how to you get basic info about it?","options":[{"text":"`myCursor.stats()`","correct":false},{"text":"`myCursor.dump()`","correct":false},{"text":"`myCursor.info()`","correct":false},{"text":"`myCursor.explain()`","correct":true}],"illustrator":""},{"question":". What is true about indexes?","options":[{"text":"They speed up read access while slowing down writes.","correct":true},{"text":"They secure the database from intruders.","correct":false},{"text":"They speed up reads and writes.","correct":false},{"text":"They speed up write access while slowing down reads.","correct":false}],"illustrator":""},{"question":". What is the preferred format to store geospatial data in MongoDB?","options":[{"text":"Latitude, longitude","correct":false},{"text":"XML","correct":false},{"text":"GeoJSON","correct":true},{"text":"BSON","correct":false}],"illustrator":""},{"question":". Which programming language is used to write MongoDB queries? (_Alternative_: In the MongoDB shell, what programming language is used to make queries?)","options":[{"text":"Python","correct":false},{"text":"JavaScript","correct":true},{"text":"SQL","correct":false},{"text":"TypeScript","correct":false}],"illustrator":""},{"question":". You have two text fields in your document and you'd like both to be quickly searchable. What should you do?","options":[{"text":"Create a text index on each field.","correct":true},{"text":"MongoDB is not able to do this.","correct":false},{"text":"Create a compound text index using both fields.","correct":false},{"text":"Create a text index on one field and a single field index on the other.","correct":false}],"illustrator":""},{"question":". To import a CSV file into MongoDB, which command should you issue?","options":[{"text":"mongorestore","correct":false},{"text":"mongoi","correct":false},{"text":"upload","correct":false},{"text":"mongoimport","correct":true}],"illustrator":""},{"question":". In an MongoDB mapReduce command, the reduce function should \\_\\_\\_\\_.","options":[{"text":"access the database","correct":false},{"text":"be called only when the key has a single value","correct":false},{"text":"access the database only to perform read operations","correct":false},{"text":"not access the data","correct":true}],"illustrator":""},{"question":". On a newly created collection, which field will have an index?","options":[{"text":"the name field","correct":false},{"text":"the ObjectId field","correct":false},{"text":"the \\_id field","correct":true},{"text":"no field will have an index","correct":false}],"illustrator":""},{"question":". You have a collection of thousands of students. You'd like to return the second set of 20 documents from the sorted collection. What is the proper order in which to apply the operations?","options":[{"text":"limit, skip, sort","correct":false},{"text":"sort, limit, skip","correct":false},{"text":"limit, sort, skip","correct":false},{"text":"sort, skip, limit","correct":true}],"illustrator":""},{"question":". You would like the stats() command to return kilobytes instead of bytes. Which command should you run?","options":[{"text":"`db.vehicle.stats(1024)`","correct":true},{"text":"`db.vehicle.stats(\"kilobytes\")`","correct":false},{"text":"`db.vehicle.stats(true)`","correct":false},{"text":"`db.vehicle.stats(\"kb\")`","correct":false}],"illustrator":""},{"question":". You want to modify an existing index. What is the best way to do this?","options":[{"text":"Use the `reIndex()` command to modify the index.","correct":false},{"text":"Delete the original index and create a new index.","correct":true},{"text":"Call the `createIndex()` command with the update option.","correct":false},{"text":"Use the `updateIndex()` command.","correct":false}],"illustrator":""},{"question":". You need to delete the index you created on the description field. Which command will accomplish this?","options":[{"text":"`db.vehicle.dropIndex(\"description_text\")`","correct":true},{"text":"`db.vehicle.dropIndex({\"description\":\"text\"})`","correct":false},{"text":"`db.vehicle.removeIndex({\"description\":\"text\"})`","correct":false},{"text":"`db.vehicle.removeIndex(\"description_text\")`","correct":false}],"illustrator":""},{"question":". You would like to know how many different categories you have. Which query will best get the job done?","options":[{"text":"`db.vehicle.distinct(\"category\")`","correct":false},{"text":"`db.vehicle.unique(\"category\")`","correct":false},{"text":"`db.vehicle.distinct(\"category\").count()`","correct":true},{"text":"`db.vehicle.distinct(\"category\").length`","correct":false}],"illustrator":""},{"question":". From the MongoDB shell, how do you create a new document in the customers collection?","options":[{"text":"`db.customers.add({name: \"Bob\"})`","correct":false},{"text":"`db.customers.save({name: \"Bob\"})`","correct":false},{"text":"`db.customers.create({name: \"Bob\"})`","correct":true},{"text":"`db.customers.new({name: \"Bob\"})`","correct":false}],"illustrator":""},{"question":". Which field is required of all MongoDB documents?","options":[{"text":"\\_id","correct":true},{"text":"\\_name","correct":false},{"text":"ObjectId","correct":false},{"text":"mongoDB is schema-less so no field is required","correct":false}],"illustrator":""},{"question":". A MongoDB instance has at least what three files?","options":[{"text":"data, namespace, and journal","correct":true},{"text":"namespace, journal, and log","correct":false},{"text":"journal, data, and database","correct":false},{"text":"data, log, and journal","correct":false}],"illustrator":""},{"question":". You'd like a set of documents to be returned in last name, ascending order. Which query will accomplish this?","options":[{"text":"`db.persons.find().sort({lastName: -1}}`","correct":false},{"text":"`db.persons.find().sort({lastName: 1}}`","correct":true},{"text":"`db.persons.find().sort({lastName: ascending}}`","correct":false},{"text":"`db.persons.find().sort({lastName: $asc}}`","correct":false}],"illustrator":""},{"question":". What is NOT a standard role in MongoDB?","options":[{"text":"restore","correct":false},{"text":"read/write","correct":false},{"text":"dbadmin","correct":true},{"text":"delete collections","correct":false}],"illustrator":""},{"question":". Which MongoDB shell command deletes a single document?","options":[{"text":"`db.customers.delete({_id: 1});`","correct":false},{"text":"`db.customers.drop({_id: 1});`","correct":false},{"text":"`db.drop.customers({_id: 1});`","correct":false},{"text":"`db.customers.remove({_id: 1});`","correct":true}],"illustrator":""},{"question":". Using the MongoDB shell, how do you remove the customer collection and its indexes?","options":[{"text":"`db.customers.remove({}).indexes();`","correct":false},{"text":"`db.customers.remove({});`","correct":false},{"text":"`db.customers.drop();`","correct":true},{"text":"`db.customers.delete();`","correct":false}],"illustrator":""},{"question":". By default, applications direct their read operations to which member of the replica set?","options":[{"text":"primary","correct":false},{"text":"arbiter","correct":true},{"text":"secondary","correct":false},{"text":"backup","correct":false}],"illustrator":""},{"question":". You need to get the names of all the indexes on your current collection. What is the best way to accomplish this?","options":[{"text":"`db.people.getName();`","correct":false},{"text":"`db.people.reIndex({names: 1});`","correct":false},{"text":"`db.people.getIndexKeys();`","correct":true},{"text":"`db.people.getIndexes();`","correct":false}],"illustrator":""},{"question":". You are going to do a series of updates to multiple records. You find setting the multi option of the update() command too tiresome. What should you do instead?","options":[{"text":"Use the replaceMany() command instead","correct":false},{"text":"Use the updateMulti() command instead","correct":false},{"text":"Use the updateMany() command instead","correct":true},{"text":"Set the global multi option to True","correct":false}],"illustrator":""},{"question":". To cleanly shut down MongoDB, what command should you use from the MongoDB shell?","options":[{"text":"quit()","correct":false},{"text":"exit()","correct":false},{"text":"db.shutdownServer()","correct":true},{"text":"db.shutdown()","correct":false}],"illustrator":""},{"question":". Given a customer collection which includes fields for gender and city, which aggregate pipeline shows the number of female customers in each city? (_Alternative_: How can you view the execution performance statistics for a query?)","options":[{"text":"`db.members.aggregate([ {$match: {gender: \"Female\"}}, {$group: {_id: {city: \"$city\"}, number: {$sum: 1}}}, {$sort :{number: -1}}])`","correct":true},{"text":"`db.members.find({$match: {gender: \"Female\"}}, {$group: {\\_id: {city: \"$city\"}, number: {$sum: 1}}}.$sort ({number: -1})`","correct":false},{"text":"`db.members.find([ {$match: {gender: \"Female\"}}, {$group: {_id: {city: \"$city\"}, number: {$sum: 1}}}, {$sort :{number: -1}}])`","correct":false},{"text":"`db.members.aggregate([ {$match: {gender: \"Female\"}}, {$sort :{number: -1}}])`","correct":false}],"illustrator":""},{"question":". When no parameters are passed to `explain()`, what mode does it run in?","options":[{"text":"wireTiger mode","correct":false},{"text":"executionStats mode","correct":false},{"text":"queryPlanner mode","correct":false},{"text":"allPlansExecution mode","correct":false}],"illustrator":""},{"question":". What is the correct query to find all of the people who have a home phone number defined?","options":[{"text":"`db.person.find({exists: 'homePhone'});`","correct":false},{"text":"`db.person.exists({homePhone: true});`","correct":false},{"text":"`db.person.find({homePhone: {$exists: true}});`","correct":true},{"text":"`db.person.has('homePhone');`","correct":false}],"illustrator":""},{"question":". Which file in the MongoDB directly holds the MongoDB daemon?","options":[{"text":"mongodb","correct":false},{"text":"mongo-daemon","correct":false},{"text":"daemon","correct":false},{"text":"mongod","correct":false}],"illustrator":""},{"question":". You have just secured your previously unsecured MongoDB server, but the server is still not requiring authentication. What is the best option?","options":[{"text":"Restart the `mongod` process.","correct":true},{"text":"Issue the `secure()` command.","correct":false},{"text":"Issue the `mongoimport` command.","correct":false},{"text":"Issue the `authenticate()` command.","correct":false}],"illustrator":""},{"question":". What is the most accurate statement regarding MongoDB and ad hoc queries?","options":[{"text":"MongoDB does not allow ad hoc queries; all queries require an index.","correct":false},{"text":"Ad hoc queries are allowed only in the paid version.","correct":false},{"text":"Ad hoc queries are allowed only through the ad hoc command.","correct":false},{"text":"MongoDB allows ad hoc queries.","correct":false}],"illustrator":""},{"question":". In MongoDB, what does a projection do?","options":[{"text":"allows you to do a calculation on the results","correct":false},{"text":"allows you to run queries on the server","correct":false},{"text":"allows you to select which fields should be in the return data","correct":false},{"text":"allows you to format the results for a display","correct":false}],"illustrator":""},{"question":". To remove a database and all of its records from MongoDB, what operator should you use?","options":[{"text":"`dropDatabase()`","correct":false},{"text":"`removeAll()`","correct":false},{"text":"`clear()`","correct":false},{"text":"`deleteDatabase()`","correct":false}],"illustrator":""},{"question":". What option can be passed to start the MongoDB shell without connecting to a database?","options":[{"text":"`-db=null`","correct":false},{"text":"`--shell-only`","correct":false},{"text":"`--free`","correct":false},{"text":"`-nodb`","correct":false}],"illustrator":""},{"question":". How can you improve the appearance of the output JSON that contains the \\_id?","options":[{"text":"`Use db.collection.set({$_id:pretty})`","correct":false},{"text":"`Create a second index`","correct":false},{"text":"`Use db.collection.format(numeric)`","correct":false},{"text":"`Use $_id = value`","correct":false}],"illustrator":""},{"question":". What happens to a Replica set oplog if it runs out of memory?","options":[{"text":"`The oplog will be saved on one of the secondary servers.`","correct":false},{"text":"`The oplog is capped collection and can't run out of memory`","correct":false},{"text":"`The MongoDB instance will fail`","correct":false},{"text":"`The oplog will stop recording logging information`","correct":false}],"illustrator":""},{"question":". MongoDB ships with a variety of files. Which file runs the MongoDB shell?","options":[{"text":"mongo","correct":true},{"text":"mongo-s","correct":false},{"text":"shell","correct":false},{"text":"mongo-shell","correct":false}],"illustrator":""},{"question":". How can you view the execution performance statistics for a query?","options":[{"text":"`db.performance.members.aggregate([ {$match: {gender: \"Female\"}}, {$group: {_id:{city:\"$city\"}, number: {$sum: 1}}}, {$sort : {number: -1}}])`","correct":false},{"text":"`db.members.aggregate([ {$match: {gender: \"Female\"}}, {$group: {_id: {city: \"$city\"}, number:{$sum:1}}}, {$sort: {number:-1}}]).explain(\"executionStats\")`","correct":false},{"text":"`db.members.aggregate([ {$match: {gender: \"Female\"}}, {$group:{_id: {city: \"$city\"}, number: {$sum: 1}}}, {$sort: {number: -1}}]).explain()`","correct":false},{"text":"`db.members.aggregate([ {$match: {gender: \"\"\"Female\"\"\"}}, {$group: {_id: {city: \"\"\"$city\"\"\"}, number: {$sum:1}}}, {$sort: {number: -1}}]).number()`","correct":false}],"illustrator":""}]